So I'm excited to talk
today about our recent work
on using transformers for
reinforcement learning.
And this is joint work with
a bunch of really exciting
collaborators, most of
them at UC Berkeley,
and some of them at
Facebook, and Google.
I should mention, this
work was led by very two
talented undergrads--
Lili Chen and Kevin Lu.
And I'm excited to present
the results we had.
So let's try to motivate why we
even care about this problem.
So we have seen in the
last three or four years
that transformers, since
their introduction in 2017,
have taken over lots and
lots of different fields
of artificial intelligence.
So we saw them having a big
impact for language processing.
We saw them being used
for vision, in the vision
transformer very recently.
They were in nature trying
to solve protein folding.
And very soon they might just
replace us computer scientists
by having automatically
generate code.
So with all of
these advances, it
seems like we are
getting closer to having
a unified model
for decision making
for artificial intelligence.
But artificial
intelligence is much
more about not just
having perception but also
using the perception
knowledge to make decisions.
And this is what this
talk is going to be about.
But before I go into
actually thinking
about how we will use these
models for decision making,
here is a motivation
for why I think it is
important to ask this question.
So unlike models
for RL, when we look
at transformers for
perception modalities
like I showed in
the previous slide,
we find that these
models are very scalable
and have very stable
training dynamics.
So you can keep-- as long as
you have enough computation
and you have more and more
data that can be sourced.
you can train bigger
and bigger models.
And you'll see very smooth
reductions in the loss.
And the overall training
dynamics are very, very stable.
And this makes it very easy for
practitioners and researchers
to build these models
and learn richer
and richer distributions.
So like I said, all
of these advances
have so far occurred
in perception.
What we're interested
in this talk
is to think about how we can
go from perception, looking
at images, looking at
text, and all these kinds
of sensory signals to then
going into the field of actually
taking actions and
making our agents
do interesting
things in the world.
And here, throughout
the talk, we
should be thinking about why
this perspective is going
to enable us to do scalable
learning, like I showed
in the previous slide,
otherwise bringing stability
into the whole procedure.
So sequential decision
making is a very broad area.
And what I'm specifically
going to be focusing on today,
is one route to sequential
decision making,
that's reinforcement learning.
So just as a brief background,
what is reinforcement learning?
So we are given an agent
who is in a current state.
And the agent is going to
interact with the environment
by taking actions.
And by taking these
actions, the environment
is going to return to
it a reward for how good
that action was, as well as
the next state into which
the agent will transition.
And this whole feedback
loop will continue on.
The goal here for
an intelligent agent
is to then, using
trial and error,
so try out different actions,
see what rewards it leads to,
learn a policy, which maps
your states to actions such
that the policy maximizes the
agent's cumulative rewards
over time horizon.
So you take a
sequence of actions.
And then based on the
reward you accumulate
for that sequence
of actions, we'll
judge how good your policy is.
This talk is also going
to be specifically focused
on a form of
reinforcement learning
that goes by the name of
offline reinforcement learning.
So the idea here is
that what changes
from the previous picture
where I was talking
about online learning, online
reinforcement learning is that
here, now instead
of doing actively
interacting with
the environment,
you have a collection of
log data of interactions.
So think about some robot
that's going out in the fields.
And it collects a
bunch of sensory data.
And you have all logged it.
And using that log data, you
now want to train another agent,
it could be another
robot, to then learn
something interesting
about that environment
just by looking at log data.
So there's no trial
and error component,
which is currently one of the
extensions of this framework,
which would be very exciting.
So I'll talk about this towards
the end of the talk, why it's
exciting to think about how
we can extend this framework
to include an
exploration component
and have trial and error.
OK, so now to go more
concretely into what
the motivating challenge
of this talk was now
that we've introduced RL.
So let's look at
some statistics.
So large language models, they
have billions of parameters.
And they have roughly about
100 layers in transformer.
They're very stable to train
using supervised learning style
losses, which are
the building blocks
of autoregressive
generation, for instance,
or for masked language
modeling as input.
And this is like a field
that's growing every day.
And there is a
course at Stanford
that we're all taking
just because it has had
such a monumental impact on AI.
RL policies on the other hand,
and I'm talking about deep RL.
The maximum they would
extend to is maybe
millions of parameters
or 20 layers.
And what's really
unnerving is that they're
very unstable to train.
So the current algorithms
for reinforcement learning,
they build on mostly
dynamic programming,
which involves following
an inner loop optimization
problem that's very unstable.
And it's very common
to see practitioners
in RL looking at rewards
that look like this.
So what I really
want you to see here
is the variance in the returns
that we tend to get in RL.
It's really huge even
after doing multiple rounds
of experimentation.
And that is really at
the core with the fact
that our algorithms [INAUDIBLE]
need better improvements
so that the performance can
be stably achieved by agents
in complex environments.
So what this work
is hoping to do
is it's going to
introduce transformers.
And I'll first show,
in one slide, what
exactly that model looks like.
And we're going to go into
deeper details of each
of the components.
I have a question.
Yeah, can I ask a
question real quick?
Yes.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
I'm curious to know what is
the cause for why RL typically
has several orders of
magnitude fewer parameters?
That's a great question.
So typically, when you think
about reinforcement learning
algorithms, in deep
RL in particular,
so the most common
algorithms, for example,
have different networks playing
different roles in the task.
So you'll have a
network, for instance,
playing the role of an actor.
So it's trying to
figure out a policy.
And then there'll be a
different network that's
playing the role of the critic.
And these networks
are trained on data
that's adaptively gathered.
So unlike perception, where
you will have a huge data
set of interactions on which
you can train your models,
in this case, the architectures
and even the environments
to some extent are very
simplistic because of the fact
that we are trying to train very
small components, the functions
that we are training and then
bringing them all together.
And these functions are often
trained in not super complex
environments.
So it's a mix of
different issues.
I wouldn't say it's purely
just got to do with the fact
that the learning
objectives are at fault,
but it's a combination of
the environments we use,
the combination of
the targets that each
of the neural networks
are predicting,
which leads to
networks which are
much bigger than
what we currently
see tending to all fit.
And that's why it's very
common to see neural networks
with much fewer layers
being used in RL
as opposed to perception.
Thank you.
You want to ask a question?
Yeah.
Yeah, I was going to.
Is there a reason why you chose
a offline RL versus online RL?
That's another great question.
So the question is why offline
RL as opposed to online RL.
And the plain reason
is because this
is the first work trying to
look at reinforcement learning.
So offline RL avoids this
problem of exploration.
You are given a large
data set of interactions.
You're not allowed to further
interact with the environment.
So just from this
data set, you are
trying to unearth a policy of
what the optimal agent would
look like.
So it would be--
Like if you do online RL
wouldn't that like just
give you this opportunity
of exploration, basically?
It would, it would.
But what it would also do, which
is technically challenging here
is that the exploration
would be harder to encode.
So offline RL is a first step.
There's no reason why we should
not study RL online or cannot
be done.
It's just that it provides
a more contained state
of where ideas from transformers
will directly extend.
OK, sounds good.
So let's look at the model.
And it's really
simple on purpose.
So what we're going
to do is we're
going to look at our offline
data, which is essentially
in the form of trajectories.
So offline data would look like
a sequence of states, actions,
returns, over
multiple time steps.
It's a sequence.
So it's natural to think
of as directly feeding it
as input to a transformer.
In this case, we use
a causal transformer
as it's common in GPT.
So we go from left to right.
And because this data set comes
with the notion of time step
causality, here it's
much more well-intended
than the general meaning
that used for perception.
This is really
causality, how it should
be in the perspective of time.
What we predict out
of this transformer
are the actions
conditioned on everything
that comes before that
token in the sequence.
So if you want to predict the
action at this t minus 1 step,
we will use everything that
came at timestep t minus 2
as well as the returns and
states at timestep t minus 1.
OK, so I will go into the
details of how exactly
each of these are encoded.
But essentially, this
is in a one liner.
It's taking the trajectory
data from the offline data,
treating it as a
sequence of tokens,
passing it through a
causal transformer,
and getting a sequence
of actions as the output.
OK, so how exactly do
we do the forward pass
through the network?
So one important
aspect of this work,
which is the usestate,
actions, and this quantity
called returns-to-go.
So these are not direct rewards.
These are returns-to-go.
And let's see what
they really mean.
So this is a trajectory that
goes as input to the system.
And the returns-to-go
are the sum
of rewards starting from
the current time step
until the end of the episode.
So really what we want the
transformer is to get better
at using a target
return, this is
how you should think
of returns-to-go,
as the input in deciding
what action to take.
This perspective is going
to have multiple advantages.
It will allow us to actually
do much more than offline RL
and generalizing to
different tasks by just
changing the returns-to-go.
And here it's very important.
So at time step 1, we will just
have the overall sum of rewards
for the entire trajectory.
At time step 2, we
subtract the reward
we get by taking
the first action
and then have the sum of
rewards for the remainder
of the trajectory.
OK, so that's why we
call it returns-to-go,
like how many more
rewards in accumulation
you need to acquire to fulfill
your reward, your return goal
that you set in the beginning.
What is the output?
The output is the sequence
of predicted actions.
So as I showed in
the previous slide,
we used a call to the
transformer so we'll predict,
in sequence, the
desired actions.
The attention which is
going to be computed
inside the transformer will take
in an important hyperparameter
K, which is the context length.
We see that in
perception as well here.
And for the rest
of the talk, I'm
going to use the notation K
to denote how many tokens,
in the past, would
be attending over
to predict the action
and the current timestep.
OK, so again, digging a
little bit deeper into code,
there are some
subtle differences
with how a decision
transformer operates as opposed
to a normal transformer.
The first is that here
the timestep notion
is going to have much
bigger semantics that
extends across three tokens.
So in perception, you just think
about the timestep for word,
for instance like in
NLP or patch for vision.
And in this case, we
will have a timestep
encapsulating three tokens.
One for the states.
One for the actions.
And one for the rewards.
And then we'll embed
each of these tokens.
And then add the position
embedding as it's
coming in the transformer.
And we feed those inputs
to the transformer.
At the output, we
only care about one
of these feed tokens
in this default setup.
I will show
experiments where even
the other tokens might be of
interest as target predictions.
But for now, let's
keep it simple.
We want to learn a policy,
a policy of just trying
to predict actions.
So when we try to decode, we'll
only be looking at the actions
from the hidden representation
in the final layer.
OK, so this is the forward pass.
Now what do we do
with this network?
We train it.
How do we train it?
Just a quick
question on semantics
there, if you go back one
slide, the plus in this case,
the syntax means
that you are actually
adding the values elementwise
wise and not concatenating,
is that right?
That is correct.
OK, just wanted to check.
OK, so what's the loss function?
Hold up on that.
I thought it was concatenating,
why are we just adding it?
Sorry, can you go back?
Yeah, I think it's
a design choice.
You can concatenate.
You can add it.
It leads to different
functions being encoded.
In our case, it is addition.
OK.
Did you try the other one
and it just didn't work
or why is that?
Because I think,
intuitively, concatenating
would make more sense.
So I think both of them
have different use cases
for the functional encoding.
Like one is really mixing in
the embeddings for the state
and basically shifting it.
So when you add
something, if you
think of the embedding
of the states as a vector
and you add something, you
are actually shifting it.
Whereas in the
concatenation case,
you are actually increasing the
dimensionality of this space.
So those are different
choices which are
doing very different things.
We found this one to be better.
I'm not sure I remember if the
results was very significantly
different if you would
concatenate them,
but this is the one
which we operate with.
But wouldn't there-- because
if you're shifting it,
like if you have an
embedding for a state,
and let's say you
perform certain actions,
and you like end up at
the same state again,
you would want these
embeddings to be the same.
However, now you're at
a different timestep,
so like you shifted it.
So wouldn't that be
like harder to learn?
So there's a bigger and
interesting question in that.
What you said is basically are
we losing the Markov property?
Because as you said that if
you come back to the same state
at a different
timestep, shouldn't we
be doing similar operations?
And the answer here is, yes.
We are actually
being non-Markov.
And this might seem very
non-intuitive at first
that why is non-Markovness
important here?
And I want to refer
to another paper which
came very much in conjunction
with this type of transformer
that actually shows
in more detail.
And it's basically
saying that if you
were trying to predict
the transition dynamics,
then you could have actually
had a Markovian system built
in here, which would
do just as good.
However, from the perspective
of trying to actually predict
actions, it does help to look
at the previous timesteps,
even more so when you
have missing observations.
So for instance, if you
have the observations being
a subset of the true state, so
looking at the previous states
and actions helps you
better fill in the missing
pieces in some sense.
So this is commonly known as
partial observability, where
by looking at the
previous tokens,
you can do a better
job at predicting
the actions you should take
at the current timestep.
So non-Markovness is on purpose.
And it's not
intuitive, but I think
it's one of the things that
separates this framework
from existing ones.
So it will basically help you--
because like RL usually works
better on infinite horizon
problems, right?
So technically, the
way you formulate it,
it would work better on finite
horizon problems, I'm assuming.
Because you want to take
different actions based
on a history, based
on given the fact
that now you would look
at a different time step.
Yeah.
Yeah, so if you wanted to
work on infinite horizon,
maybe something like this
would work just as well
to get that effect.
In this case, we were using
a discount factor of 1
or basically like no
discounting at all.
But you're right,
if I think we really
want to extend it
to infinite horizon,
we would need to change
the discount factor.
OK, thanks.
Quick question.
I think it was just
answered in chat.
But I'll ask it anyways.
I think I might have
missed this or maybe you're
about to talk about it.
The offline data that
was collected, what
policy was used to collect it?
So this is a very
important question.
And it will be something I
mention in the experiment.
So we were using the benchmarks
that exist for offline RL.
Essentially, the
various benchmarks
are constructed as you train
an agent using online RL.
And then you look at its
replay buffer at some timestep,
so while it's training.
So while it's like a
medium sort of expert,
you collect the transitions,
its experience so far.
And that is the offline data.
It's something which is--
our framework is
very agnostic to what
offline data that we use.
So I'm not discussing so far.
But something that
in our experiments
is based on
traditional benchmarks.
Got it.
So the reason I ask is I'm
sure that your framework can
accommodate any offline data.
But it seems to me like
the results that you're
about to present are going to
be heavily contingent on what
that data collection policy is.
Indeed, indeed.
And also we will--
I think I have a slide
where we show an experiment
where the amount of data
can make a difference in how
we compare with baselines.
And essentially, we will see how
decision transformer especially
shines when there is small
amounts of offline data.
OK, cool.
Thank you.
OK, great questions.
So let's go ahead.
So we have defined our
model which is going
to look at these trajectories.
And now, let's see
how we train it.
So very simple.
We are trying to
predict actions.
We'll try to match them to the
ones we have in our data set.
If they are continuous,
using the mean squared error.
If they are discrete then
we can use a cross-entropy.
So but there is something very
deep in here for RL research,
which is that these objectives
are very stable to train
and easy to regularize
because they've been developed
for supervised learning.
In contrast, what
RL is more used to
is dynamic programming
style objectives,
which are based on
the Bellman equation.
And those end up being much
harder to optimize and scale.
And that's why you see a lot
of the variance in the results
as well.
OK, so this is how
we train the model.
Now, how do we use the model?
And that's the
point about trying
to do rollout for the model.
So here again, this is
going to be similar to doing
an autoregressive generation.
There is an
important token here,
which was the returns-to-go.
And what we need to
set during evaluation,
presumably, we want
expert level performance
because that will have
the highest returns.
So we set the initial
returns-to-go not
based on that trajectory,
because now we
don't have a trajectory.
We're in a generator trajectory.
So this is at inference time.
So we will set it to the
expert return for instance.
So in code, what this
whole procedure would
look like is basically you
set this returns-to-go token
to some target return.
And you set your
initial state to one
from the environment
distribution of initial states.
And then you just roll out
your decision transformer.
So you get a new action.
And this action will
also give you a state
and reward from the environment.
You append them
to your sequence.
And you get a new returns-to-go.
And you take just
the context in K
because that's what's used
by the transformer to making
predictions and
then feed it back
to the decision transformer.
So it's regular
autoregressive generation,
but the only key point to
notice is how you initialize
the transformer for RL.
Sorry, I have one question here.
So how much does the choice
of the expert targeted
return matter?
Does it have to be like
the mean expected reward
or can it be like the maximum
reward possible in [INAUDIBLE]??
Does the choice of the
number really matter?
That's a very good question.
So we generally would set it to
be slightly higher than the max
return in the data set.
So I think the factor
that we use 1.1 times.
But I think we have done
a lot of experimentation
in the range.
And it's fairly robust
to what choice you use.
So for example we hope our
expert returns about 3,600.
And we have found ways
to improve performance
from all the way
from like 3,500,
3,400 to even going to very high
numbers like 5,000, it works.
Yeah, so however, I
would want to point out
that this is something which
is not typically needed
in regular RL, like
knowing the expert return.
Here we are actually going
beyond regular RL in that we
can choose a return we want.
So we also actually
need this information
about what the expert return is.
There's another question?
Yes, so just to kind of
be on the regular RL.
But I'm curious
about do you also
like restrict this
framework to only offline RL
because if you want to run
this kind of framework in RL,
you have to determine the
returns-to-go a priori.
So this kind of
framework I think
is restricted to only
offline RL, do you think so?
Yes, and I think asking this
question as well earlier
that, yes, I think for now,
this is the first step.
So we were focusing
on offline RL
where this information can be
gathered from the offline data
set.
It is possible to
think about strategies
on how you can even
get this online,
what you'll need
is a curriculum.
So early on during training
as you're gathering data, when
you're doing rollouts, you
will set your expert return
to whatever you see in the data
set, and then increment it as
and when you start seeing that
the transformer can actually
exceed the performance.
So you can think of
specifying a curriculum
from slow to high for what
that expert return could
be for which you roll out
the decision transformer.
That's cool, thank you.
So yeah, this was
about the model.
So we discussed
how this model is,
what the input to this model
are, what the outputs are,
what the loss function is
used for training this model,
and how do we use this
model at test time.
There is a connection
to this framework
as being one way
to instantiate what
is often known as RL as
probabilistic inference.
So we can formulate RL as a
graphical model problem, where
you have the states and
actions being used to determine
what the next state is.
And to encode a
notion of optimality,
typically you would also have
these additional auxiliary
variables--
O1, O2, and so on,
and forth, which
are implicitly saying that
encoding some notion of reward.
And conditioned on this
optimality being true,
RL is the task of
learning a policy which
is the mapping from
states to actions such
that we get optimal behavior.
And if you really
squint your eyes,
you can see that these
optimality variables
in decision transformers,
are actually being
encoded by the returns-to-go.
So if when we give a value
that's high enough at test time
during rollout, like
the expert return,
we are essentially
saying that conditioned
on this being the
mathematical form
quantification of
optimality, roll out
your decision transformer
to hopefully satisfy
this condition.
So yeah, so this was all I
want to talk about the model--
Can you explain that, please?
What do you mean by optimality
variables in the decision
transformer?
And how do you mean
like returns-to-go?
Right, so optimality
variables, we
can think in the most simplest
context, as-- let's just
say they were binary.
So 1 is if you solve the goal.
And 0 is if you did
not solve the goal.
And basically in that
case, you could also
think of your
decision transformer
as at test time when we
encode the returns-to-go,
we could set it to 1.
Which would basically mean
that conditioned on optimality
here means solving
the goal as 1.
Generate me the
sequence of actions
such that this would be true.
Of course our learning
is not perfect.
So it's not guaranteed
we'll get that.
But we have trained
the transformer
in a way to interpret
the returns-to-go
as some notion of optimality.
So if I'm interpreting
this correctly,
it's roughly like
saying, show me
what an optimal
sequence of transitions
look like because you've
learned-- the model has learned
sort of both successful and
unsuccessful transitions.
Exactly, exactly.
And as we shall see
in some experiments,
for the binary case, it's
either optimal or non optimal.
But rarely this can be
a continuous variable,
which it is in our experiments.
So we can also see what happens
in between experimentally.
OK, so let's jump
into the experiments.
So there are a bunch
of experiments.
And I've picked
out a few which I
think are interesting and give
the key results in the paper.
But feel free to
reference the paper
for an even more
detailed analysis on some
of the components of our model.
So first we can look at how well
they're doing in offline RL.
So there are benchmarks for
the Atari suite of environments
and the OpenAI Gym.
And we have another
environment Key-To-Door
which is especially hard because
it contains sparse rewards
and requires it to do
credit assignment that I'll
talk about later.
But across the board, we see
that decision transformer
is competitive with the state
of the art model-free offline RL
methods.
In this case, this was
a version of Q-learning
designed for offline RL.
And it can do
excellent especially
when there is long term
credit assignment where
traditional methods based
on TD learning would fail.
Yeah, so the takeaway
here should not
be that we should
be at the stage
where we can just
substitute the existing
algorithms with the
decision transformer,
but this is very strong
evidence in favor
that this paradigm which
is building on transformers
will permit us to better
iterate and improve
the models to hopefully
surpass the existing algorithms
uniformly.
And there's some early evidence
of that in hard environments
which do require long
term credit assignment.
May I ask a question here about
the baseline, specifically,
TD learning.
I'm curious to
know, because I know
that a lot of TD learning
agents are feedforward networks.
Are these baselines?
Do they have recurrence?
Yeah, yeah.
So I think the conservative
Q-learning baselines here
did have recurrence,
but I'm not very sure.
So I can check back on this
offline and get back to you
on this.
OK, OK, thank you. .
Also another quick question.
So just how exactly do
you evaluate the decision
transformer here
in the experiment,
because you need to
supply the returns-to-go,
so you didn't use
the optimal policy
to get what's the optimal
rewards, which feed that in?
So here, we basically
look at the offline data
set that is used for training.
And we said whatever
was the maximum return
in the offline data, we
set the desired target
return to go as slightly
higher than that.
So 1.1 I think was the
coefficient we used.
I see.
And the performance sorry, I'm
not really well versed in RL.
So how is the
performance defined here?
Is it how much reward
you get actually from--
Yes, yes.
So you can specify a
target return to go,
but there's no guarantee that
the actual actions that you
take will achieve that return.
So you actually you measure
the true environmental return
based on that.
Yeah, I see.
But then just curiously,
so are these performance
the percentage you get,
like how much, I guess,
reward you recover from
the actual environments?
Yeah, so these are
not percentages.
These are some way of
normalizing the returns
so that everything
falls between 0 to 100.
Yeah, yeah.
Just wondering if
you have a rough idea
of how much reward
actually is recovered
by decision transformers?
Does it say like, if you specify
I want to get 50 rewards,
does it get 49?
Or is it even
better sometimes or?
That's an excellent
question and my next slide.
So here, we're going to
answer precisely this question
that we're asked is like,
if you're feeding the target
return, it could be expert or
it could also not be expert.
How well does the model
actually do in attaining it?
So the x-axis is what we specify
as the target return we want.
And the y-axis is basically
how well do we actually get?
For reference, we have this
green line, which is the Oracle
so which means
whatever you desire,
the decision transformer
gives it to you.
So this would have
been the ideal case.
So it's a diagonal.
We also have, because
this is offline RL,
we have, in orange, what was
the best trajectory data set.
So the offline data
is not perfect.
So we just plot what is the
upper bound on the offline data
performance.
And here, we find that for the
majority of the environments,
there is a good fit between
the target return we feed in
and the actual
performance of the model
And there are some
other observations
which I wanted to take from the
slide is that because we can
vary this notion of reward,
we can, in some sense,
do multi-task RL via
return conditioning.
This is not the only
way to do multitask RL,
you can specify a task
via natural language,
you can specify by a goal
state, and so on, and so forth.
But this is one notion
where the notion of a task
could be how much
reward you want.
And another thing to
notice is, occasionally,
these models extrapolate.
This is not a trend we have
been seeing consistently,
but we do see some signs of it.
So if you look at,
for example Seaquest.
Here, the highest return
trajectory in a data set
was pretty low.
And if you specify
a return higher
than that for a
decision transformer,
we do find that the
model is able to achieve.
So it is able to
generate trajectories
with returns higher than
it ever saw in the dataset.
I do believe that future
work in this space trying
to improve this model
should think about
how can the strain be more
consistent across environments
because this would really
achieve the goal of offline RL
which is given
suboptimal behavior,
how do you get optimal
behavior out of it?
But it remains to be seen how
well this trend can be made
consistent across environments.
Can I jump in with a question?
Yes.
So I think that last point
is really interesting.
And it's cool that you
guys occasionally see it.
I'm curious to
know what happens.
So this is all condition.
You give as an input what
return you would like.
And it tries to
select a sequence
of actions that gives it.
I'm curious to know what
happens if you just give it
ridiculous inputs,
like for example, here
the order of magnitude for
the return is like 50 to 100,
what happens if
you put in 10,000?
Good question.
And this is something
we tried early on.
I don't want to say
we went up to 10,000,
but we tried like
really high returns
that not even an
expert could get.
And generally, we see
this leveling performance.
So you can see hints of it in
HalfCheetah, and Pong as well,
or Walker to some extent.
If you look at the very end,
things start saturating.
So if you exceed what is
like certain threshold,
which often corresponds with
the best trajectory threshold
but not always, beyond that
everything is similar returns.
So at least one good
thing is it does not
degrade in performance.
So it would have
been a little bit
worrying if you specified
a return of 10,000
and it gives you a return which
is 20 or something really low.
So it's good that it
stabilizes, but it's not
that it keeps
increasing on and on.
So there would be a point
where the performance would
get saturated.
OK, thank you.
I was just curious.
So usually for transfer
models you need a lot of data.
So do you know like how
much data do you need,
like how well does it scale
with data, the performance,
of decision transformer?
Yeah, so here we use
the standard data
like the default RL
benchmarks for MuJoCo
which I think have
millions or transitions
in the order of millions.
For Atari, we used 1%
of the replay buffer,
which is smaller than the one we
used for the MuJoCo benchmarks.
And I actually have a result
in the very next slide, which
shows a decision transformer
especially being useful
when you have a little data.
Yeah, so I guess one
question to ask--
Before you move on,
in the last slide,
what do you mean again by return
conditioning for the multitask
part?
Yes, if you think
about the returns-to-go
at test time, the one
you have to feed in
as the starting token,
as one way of specifying
what policy you want.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
How is that multi-task?
So it is multitask
in the sense that you
can get different policies
by changing your target
return-to-go.
You're essentially getting
different behaviors included.
So think about, for instance,
the Hopper and you specify
a return-to-go that's very low.
So you're basically saying get
me an agent which will just
stick around its
initial state and not
go into uncharted territory.
And if you give it really,
really high, then you're
asking it to do the traditional
task, which is to hop
and go as far as
possible without falling.
Can you qualify
those multitasks,
because that
basically just means
that your return conditioning
is a cue for it to memorize,
right?
Which is usually one of
the pitfalls of multitask?
I'm not sure--
You need a task identifier,
that's what I'm trying to say.
I'm not sure if
it's memorization--
I think the purpose
of this, I mean
having an offline dataset
that makes it basically saying
that it's very, very specific
to if you had the same start
state, and you took
the same actions,
and you had the same
target returns, that
would qualify as memorization.
But here at test time, we allow
all of these things to change.
And in fact they do change.
So your initial state
would be different.
Your target return of it could
be a different scalar than one
you ever saw during training.
So essentially, the
model has to learn
to generate that
behavior starting
from a different
initial state and maybe
a different value
of the target return
than it saw during training.
If the dynamics are stochastic
that also makes it that.
Even if you memorize
the actions,
you're not guaranteed to
get the same next state.
So you would actually
have a bad correlation
with the performance if the
dynamics were also stochastic.
I also [INAUDIBLE]
how much time does it
take to train decision
transformer in general?
So it takes about a few hours.
So I want to say like
about four to five hours,
depending on what
quality GPU you use.
But yeah that's a
reasonable estimate.
Yeah, got it.
Thanks.
OK, so actually while
doing this project,
we thought of a
baseline which we
were surprised is not there
in previous literature
on offline RL but
makes very much sense.
And we thought we
should also think about
whether decision
transformer they're actually
doing something very
similar to that baseline.
And the baseline is what we call
as percent behavioral cloning.
So behavioral
cloning what it does
is basically it
ignores the returns
and simply imitates the agent by
just trying to map the actions
given the constraints.
This is not a good idea
with an offline data
set which will have
trajectories of both low returns
and high returns.
So traditional
behaviour cloning,
it's common to see that as a
baseline in offline RL methods.
And unless you have a very
high quality data set,
it is not a good
baseline for offline RL.
However, there is
a version that we
call as percent
BC, which actually
makes quite a lot of sense.
And in this version, we filter
out the top trajectories
from our offline dataset
and stop the ones
that have the highest rewards.
You know the rewards
for each transition.
You calculate the returns
on the trajectories.
And we take the trajectories
with the highest returns
and keep a certain
percentage of them,
which is going to be
hyperparameter here.
And once you keep those top
fraction of your trajectories,
you then just ask your
model to imitate them.
So imitation learning
also uses, especially when
it's used in the form
of behavioral cloning,
it uses supervised
learning essentially,
it's a supervised
learning problem.
So you could actually
also get supervised
learning objective functions
if you did this filtering step.
And what do you find?
Actually that for the moderate
and high data regimes,
decision transformers
are actually
very comparable to percent BC.
So it's a very strong
baseline, which
I think all of future work
in offline RL should include.
There's actually
an ICLR submission
from last week, which has a much
more detailed analysis on just
this baseline that we
introduced in this paper.
And what we do find is
that for low data regimes,
the decision transformer
does much better
than percent behavior cloning.
So this is for the
Atari benchmarks
where, like I
previously mentioned,
we have a much smaller data
set as compared to the MuJoCo
environments.
And here we find that even after
varying the different fraction
of the percentage
hyperparameter here,
we are generally not able to
get the strong performance
the decision transformer gets.
So 10% BC basically means that
we filter and keep the top 10%
of the trajectories.
If you go even lower,
then the dataset
becomes really small so the
baseline becomes meaningless.
But for even though
reasonable ranges,
we never find the
performance matching
that of decision transformers
for these Atari benchmarks.
Aditya, if I may.
So notice in table
3, for example,
which is not this
table but the one just
before it in the paper.
There's a report on the CQL
performance, which to me also
feels intuitively pretty
similar to the percent BC,
in the sense of you
pick trajectories
you know are performing
well and you try and stay
roughly within sort of
the same kind of kind
of policy distribution and
state space distribution.
I was curious on this one.
Do you have a sense of what
the CQL performance was
relative to, say, the
percent BC performance here?
So that's a great question.
So the question is
that even for CQL you
rely on this notion
of pessimism where
you want to pick trajectories
where you're more confident in.
And try to make sure policy
remains in that region.
So I don't have the numbers
of CQL on this table.
But if you look at the
detailed results for Atari,
then I think they should
have the CQL for sure,
because that's the numbers
we are reporting here.
So I can tell you what the
CQL performance is actually
pretty good and it's very
competitive with the decision
transformer for Atari.
So this TD learning
baseline here is CQL.
So by naturally by
extension, I would
imagine it's doing
better than percent BC.
Yeah, and I apologize
if this was mentioned
and I just missed it.
But do you have
the sense that this
is basically like
a failure of CQL
to be able to extrapolate well
or sort of stitch together
different parts of trajectories,
whereas the decision
transformer can sort of
make that extrapolation
between-- you have
the first half of one
trajectory is really good.
The second half of one
And so you can actually
piece those together
with the decision transform,
where you can't necessarily
do that with CQL because
the path connecting those
may not necessarily be well
covered by the behavior policy.
Yeah, yeah.
And this actually goes to one of
the intuitions which I did not
emphasize too much, but we have
a discussion on that paper,
where essentially
why do we expect
a transformer or any
model for that matter
to look at offline
data that's suboptimal
and get something
in a policy that
generates optimal rollouts?
The intuition is that,
as Scott was mentioning,
you could perhaps stitch
together good behaviors
from suboptimal trajectories.
And that stitching
could perhaps lead
to a behavior that was
better than anything
you saw in individual
trajectories in a data set.
It's something we find early
evidence of in small scale
experiments for graphs.
And that's really our
hope also that something
that the transformer
is very good at,
because it can attend
to very long sequences.
So it could identify
those segments of behavior
which when stitched
together would give you
optimal behavior.
And it's very much possible.
And that is something unique
to decision transformers.
And something like CQL would
not be able to do percent BC
because it's filtering out
the data is automatically
being limited and not
being able to do that,
because those segments
of good behavior
could be in trajectories
which overall do not
have a high return.
So if you filter them
out, you are losing out
on that information.
OK, so I said there is a
hyperparameter, the context
in K. And like with
most of perception,
one of the big advantages
of transformers as opposed
to other sequence
models like LSTMs
is that they can process
fairly large sequences.
And here at first glance, it
might seem that being Markovian
would have been helpful for RL,
which also was a question that
was raised earlier.
So we did this experiment where
we did compare performance
with context in K plus 1.
And here, we had context
length between 30
for the environments
and 50 for Pong.
And we find that increasing
the context length
is very, very important
to get good performance.
OK, now so far I've showed
you how decision transformer,
which is very simple.
There was no slide
I had, which was
going into the details of
dynamic programming, which
is the crux of most RL.
This was just pure
supervised learning
in an autoregressive
framework that was getting
us this good performance.
What about cases where
this approach actually
starts outperforming some of
the traditional methods RL?
So to probe a
little bit further,
we started looking at
sparse reward environments.
And basically, we just took our
existing MuJoCo environments.
And then instead of giving
it the information for reward
for every transition,
we Fed it the
cumulative reward at the
end of the trajectory.
So every transition will have
zero reward except the very end
where you get the
entire reward at once.
It's a very sparse reward
scenario for that reason.
And here we find that, compared
to the original dense results,
the delayed results for DT will
deteriorate a little bit, which
was expected because
now you are withholding
some of the more fine grained
information at every time step.
But the drop is not too
significant compared
to the original DT
performance here.
Whereas for something
like CQL, there
is a drastic drop
in performance.
So CQL suffers quite a lot
in sparse reward scenarios,
but decision
transformer does not.
And just for
completeness, we also
have performance of the
behavior cloning and percent
behavior cloning
because they don't
look at reward information,
except maybe percent BC
looks at only for
pre-processing the data set.
These are agnostic to
whether the environments
have sparse rewards or not.
Would you expect
this to be different
if you were doing online RL?
What's the intuition
for it being different?
A priori, I would
say no, but maybe I'm
missing out on a key piece of
intuition behind that question.
I think that because you're
training like offline,
the next input will always
be the correct action
in that sense.
So you don't just deviate
and let go off the rails
technically, because
you just don't know.
So I could see how online would
have a really hard, cold start
basically because it
just doesn't know.
And it's just
tapping in the dark
until it maybe eventually
hits the jackpot.
Right, right, I think I
agree, that's a good piece
of intuition out there.
I think here that offline
RL is really getting rid
of the trial and
error aspect of it
and for sparse reward
environments that
would be harder.
So the drop in DT performance
should be more prominent there.
I'm not sure how
it would compare
with the job performance
for other algorithms.
But it does seem like
an interesting setup
to test the gain.
Well, Aditya, maybe
I'm wrong here.
But my understanding with the
decision transformer as well as
this is the critical
piece that in the training
you use the rewards
to go, right?
So is it not the sense
that essentially like
for each trajectory, from
the initial state based
on the training
regime, the model
has access to whether or not
the final result was a success
or failure, right?
But that's a unique aspect
of the training regime
for decision transformers.
Whereas in CQL, my
understanding is
that it's based on a per
transition training regime.
So each transition
is decoupled somewhat
to what the final reward
was, is that correct?
Yes, although like
one difficulty which
at first glance you can imagine
the decision transformer
having is that
initial token will not
change throughout
the trajectory,
because it's a sparse
reward scenario.
Except the very last token
where it will drop down to 0
all of a sudden.
This token remains
the same throughout
But I think you're right that
maybe just even at the start,
feeding it in a manner which
looks at the future rewards
that you need to get to is
perhaps one part of the reason
why the drop in performance
is not noticeable.
Yeah, I mean, I guess, one
sort of ablation experiment
here would be if you
change the training
regime so that only the last
trajectory had the reward.
But I'm trying to think about
whether or not that would just
be compensated for by sort of
the attention mechanism anyway,
and vice versa, right, if
you embedded that reward
information into the
CQL training procedure
as well, I'd be curious to
see what would happen there.
Yeah, good experiments.
OK, related to this, there's
another environment we tested.
I gave you a brief preview
of the results in one
of the earlier slides.
This is called a
Key-To-Door environment.
And it has three phases.
So in the first phase, the agent
is placed in a room with a key.
A good agent will
pick up the key.
And then in phase two, it will
be placed in an empty room.
And in phase three, it will be
placed in a room with a door
where it will
actually use the key
that it collected in phase one,
if it did, to open the door.
So essentially,
the agent is going
to receive a binary reward
corresponding to whether it
reached and opened the door
in phase three, conditioned
on the fact that it did pick
up the key in phase one.
So there is this notion on
that you want to assign credit
to something that happened-- to
an event that happened really
in the past.
So it's a very challenging
and sensible scenario
if you wanted to ask the
models for how well they are
at long term credit assignment.
And here, we find that--
so we tested it for different
amounts of trajectories.
So here the number
of trajectories
basically says how often
would you actually see
this kind of behavior?
And the decision transformer
and percent behavior cloning,
both of these actually
baselines do much better
than other models which
struggle at this task.
There's a related
experiment there
which is also of interest.
So generally a lot
of other algorithms
have this notion of
an actor and a critic.
Actor is basically
someone that takes
actions, conditioned on the
states and think of a policy.
A critic is basically
evaluating how good
these actions are in terms
of achieving a long term--
in terms of the cumulative sum
of rewards in the long term.
This is a good
environment because we
can see how well the
decision transformer would do
if it was trained as a critic.
So here what we did
is, instead of having
the actions of
the output target,
what if we substituted
that with the rewards?
So that's very much possible.
We can again use the same
causal transformer machinery
to only look at transitions
in the previous timestep
and try to pick the reward.
And here, we see this
interesting pattern
where in the three
phases that we
had in that Key-To-Door
environment,
we do see the reward
probability changing very much
in how we expect.
So basically, the three
scenarios are the agent.
The first scenario,
let's look at blue,
in which the agent does not
pick up the key, in phase one.
So the reward probability
they all started on the same
but as it becomes apparent
that the agent is not
going to pick up the key,
the reward starts going down.
And then it stays
very much close to 0
throughout the
episode because there
is no way you will
have the key to open
the door in the future phases.
If you pick up the key,
there are two possibilities
which remain, which
are essentially
the same in phase two where
you are in an empty room, which
is just a distractor to make
the episode really long.
But at the very end,
the two possibilities
are one that you take
the key and you actually
reach the door, which is the
one we see in orange and brown
here, where you see that the
reward probability goes up.
And there's this
other possibility
that you actually pick up the
key but do not reach the door.
In which case, again,
we start seeing
that the reward probability
that's predicted
starts going down.
So the takeaway
from this experiment
is that decision
transformers are not
just great actors,
which is what we've
been seeing so
far in the results
from the optimized policy.
But they're also very
impressive critics
in doing this long
term assignment where
the reward is also very sparse.
So Aditya, just
to be correct, are
they predicting the rewards
to go at each timestep
or is this like
they have to make
the rewards at each timestep,
are they predicting?
So this is the rewards to go.
And I can also check--
my impression was
in this particular
experiment it didn't really
make a difference, whether you
were predicting rewards to go
or the actual rewards.
But I think it was
returns-to-go for this one.
So how do you get the
probability distribution
of the rewards?
Is it just like
you just evaluate
a lot of different episodes
and just give the rewards?
Or are you explicitly predicting
some sort of distribution?
So this is a binary
reward, so you can have--
so you can have a
probabilistic outcome.
Got it.
[INAUDIBLE] you have a question.
Yes, so generally, we
will call something
predicts a state value or
state action value as critic.
But in this case, you ask
a decision transformer
to only predict rewards.
So why choose to
call it a critic?
So I think the analogy
here gets a bit clearer
with returns-to-go.
Like if you think
about returns-to-go,
it's really capturing that
essence that you want to see
the future rewards that--
So I'm assuming it's just
going to predict the return
to go instead of single
state reward, right?
Yeah, yeah.
OK, so if you're
going to predict
returns-to-go is kind
of counterintuitive
to me, because in phase
one when the agent is still
in the key room, I think it
should have high returns-to-go
if it picked up the key.
But in the plot,
in the key room,
the agent picked up
the key and the agent
that didn't pick up key
has the same kind of level
of returns-to-go, so that's
quite counterintuitive to me.
I think this is reflecting
on a good property, which
is that your distribution--
if you interpret returns-to-go
in the right way, in phase one,
you don't know which
of these three outcomes
are really possible.
And phase one, I'm talking about
the very beginning basically,
slowly we learn about it.
But essentially, in phase one if
you see the returns-to-go as 1
or 0 for--
all three possibilities
are equally likely.
And all three possibilities--
so if we try to evaluate
the predicted rewards
for these possibilities,
it should be the same,
because we really
haven't done or we
don't know what's going
to happen in phase three.
Sorry, it's my mistake,
because previously I
thought a green line
is the agent which
doesn't pick up the key.
But it turns out the
blue line is agent
which doesn't pick up the key.
So yeah, it's my mistake.
It makes sense to me.
Thank you.
I also must note pretty
clear from the paper,
but did you do
experiments where you're
predicting what actions and
what are the rewards to go?
Can it improve performance
if it didn't work together?
So actually, we did some
preliminary experiments
on that.
And it didn't help us much.
However, I do want
to, again, put
in a plug for a paper that
came concurrently, trajectory
transformer which tried
to predict states,
actions, and rewards,
actually, all three of them.
They were in a model based
setup where it made sense also
to try to learn each of the
components like the transition
dynamics, the policy, and maybe
even the critic and their setup
together.
We did not find any
significant improvements.
So in favor of simplicity
and keeping it model free,
we did not try to
predict them together.
Got it.
OK, so the summary, we
showed decision transformers
which is a first work
in trying to approach RL
based on sequence modeling.
The main advantages
over previous approaches
is it's simple by design.
The hope is that
further extensions
we will find it to scale
much better than existing RL
algorithms.
It is stable to train, because
the loss functions we are using
have been tested and
iterated upon a lot
by research in perception.
And in the future,
we will also hope
that because of
these similarities
in the architecture
and the training
with how perception based
tasks are conducted,
it would also be easy
to integrate them
within this loop.
So the states, the actions,
or even the task of interest
they could be specified based
on perceptual based sensors.
So you could have
a target task being
specified by a natural
language instruction.
And because these
models can very well
play with these kinds
of inputs, the hope
is that they would be easy to
integrate within the decision
making process.
And empirically saw
strong performance
in a range of
offline RL settings
and especially good
performance in scenarios
which required us to do
long credit assignment.
So there's a lot of future work.
This is definitely not the end.
This is a first
work in rethinking
how do we build RL agents
that can scale and generalize.
A few things that I
picked out which I feel
would be very
exciting to extend--
the first is multi modality.
So really, one of
our big motivations
with going after
these kinds of models
is that we can combine
different kinds of inputs
both online and offline to
really build decision making
agents which work like humans.
We process so many inputs around
us in different modalities
and we act on them.
So we do take decisions.
And we want the same to
happen in artificial agents.
And maybe decision transformers
is one important step
in that route.
Multi-task, so I
showed or described
very limited form of
multitasking here,
which was based on the
desired returns-to-go.
But it could be more richer in
terms of specifying a command
to be a robot or a
desired goal state
which could be, for
example, even visual.
So trying to better explore
the different multitask
capabilities of
this model but also
be an interesting extension.
Finally, multi-agent
as human beings
we never act in isolation.
We are always acting within
an environment that involves
many, many more agents.
Things become partially
observable in those scenarios,
which plays to the strengths
of decision transformers
being non-Markovian by design.
So I think there is great
possibilities of exploring even
multi-agent scenarios where
the fact that transformers can
process very large sequences
compared to existing algorithms
could again help build
better models of other agents
in your environment and act.
Yeah, these are some
useful links in case
you're interested.
The project website, the paper,
and the code are all public.
And I'm happy to take
any more questions.
OK, so Aditya, thanks
for the good talk.
We really appreciate it.
Everyone had a good time for it.
I think we are like
near the class limit.
So usually, I have
a round of questions
for the speaker, that is like
the students usually know.
but if someone is asking you
just ask general questions
before we stop the recording.
So if anyone wants to
leave earlier at this time,
just feel free to
ask your questions.
Otherwise, I would
just like continue on.
So what do you think is the
future of like transformers
in RL?
Do you think they
will take over--
they've already taken over
like language and vision,
or like model based and
model free learning,
do you think we will see a lot
more like transformers pop up
in RL literature?
Yes, I think we'll see a
flurry of work, if not already.
There's so many works
using transformers
at this year's ICLR conference.
Having said that, I feel
that an important piece
of the puzzle that needs to
be solved is exploration.
It's non-trivial.
And it will have to,
my guess is that, you
will have to forego
some of the advantages
that I talked about
for transformers
in terms of loss functions to
actually enable exploration.
So it remains to be seen whether
those modified, those functions
for exploration actually hurt
performance significantly.
But as long as we cannot
cross that bottleneck,
I do not want to commit that
this is indeed the future of RL
Got It.
Also do you think something--
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
Can I ask a follow up question?
Sure.
I'm not sure I
understood that point.
So you're saying that in order
to apply transformers in RL
to do exploration, there have
to be particular loss functions
and they're tricky
for some reason?
Could you explain
more, like what
are the modified loss functions
and why do they seem tricky?
So essentially in
exploration you
have to do the opposite
of exploitation,
which is not greedy.
And there is right now
no nothing in-built
in the transformer
right now which
encourages that sort
of random behavior
where you seek out unfamiliar
parts of the state space.
That is something
which is inbuilt
into traditional algorithms.
So you usually have some
sort of entropy bonus
to encourage exploration.
And those are the modifications
which one will also
need to think about if
one were to use decision
transformers for online RL.
So what happens if somebody,
I mean just naively,
suppose I have this
exact same setup.
And the way that I
sample the action is I
sample epsilon greedily, or I
create a Boltzmann distribution
in my sample from that,
I mean just what happens?
It seems that's what RL
does, so does what happens?
So RL does a little
bit more than that.
It indeed does those
kinds of things
where it would change the
distribution, for example,
the Boltzmann distribution
and sample from it.
There are these, as I say,
the devil lies in the detail.
It's also about how it controls
that exploration component
with the exploitation.
It remains to be
seen whether that
is compatible with
decision transformers.
I don't want to
jump the gun, but I
would say preliminary evidence
suggests that it's not directly
transferable the exact same
setup to the online case,
that's what we have found.
There has to be some
adjustments to be made to make,
which we are still
figuring it out.
So the reason why I
ask is as you said,
the devil's in the details.
And so someone naively like me
might just come along and try
doing what's in RL.
I want to hear more about this.
So you're saying that
what works in RL may not
work for decision transformers.
Can you tell us why, like
what pathologies emerge?
What are those devils
hiding in the details?
Well, I'll tell you [INAUDIBLE]
we also over time so--
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
But like to me, that's
really exciting.
And I'm sure that it's tricky.
Yeah, I'm just asking
two more questions
and you can finish off of those.
So when do you think something
like decision transformer
is able to solve the credit
assignment problem in RL
instead of using some sort
of like discount factor?
Sorry, can you
repeat the question?
Sorry, I think
usually in RL, we have
to rely on some sort
of discount factor
to encode the rewards to
go, but decision transformer
is able to do this credit
assignment without that.
So do you think
something like this book
is like the way
you should do it,
like instead of having
some discount try
to directly predict rewards?
So I would go on
to say that I feel
a discount factor is an
important consideration
in general.
And it's not incompatible
with decision transformers.
So basically what would change,
and I think the code actually
gives that functionality
where the returns-to-go would
be computed as the
discounted sum of rewards.
And so it is very
much compatible.
So there are scenarios where
context length is still is not
enough to actually capture the
long term behavior we really
need for credit assignment.
Maybe traditional
tricks that are used
could be brought in back to
solve those kinds of problems.
Got it.
Yeah, I also thought like when
I was reading the decision
transformer that the interesting
thing is that you don't
have a fixed gamma,
like a gamma is
that usually a hyperparameter.
But you don't have
a fixed gamma,
can you also learn this thing?
And could this also be like--
can you have a different gamma
for each timestep or something,
possibly?
That would be
interesting actually.
I had not thought
of that, but maybe
learning to predict
the discount factor
could be another
extension of this work.
Also do you think like
decision transformer work,
is it compatible
with Q-learning?
So if you have something
like CQL, stuff like that,
can you also implement those
sort of loss functions on top
of a decision transformer?
Maybe I could
imagine ways in which
you could include pessimism
in here as well, which
is key to how CQL works.
And actually most of
offline RL algorithms work,
including the model based ones.
Our focus here deliberately
was to go after simplicity.
Because we feel that part of
the reason why RL literature has
been so scattered, as well
if you think about different
sub-problems that
everyone tries to solve,
has been because everyone's
tried to pick up on ideas which
are very well suited for
that narrow problem like,
for example, you have--
whether you're doing offline
RL, or you're doing online,
or you're doing
imitation, you're
doing multitask, and all
these different variants.
And so by design,
we did not want
to incorporate exactly
the components that
exist in the current algorithms,
because then it just starts
looking more like
architecture change
as opposed to a more
conceptual change
into thinking about RL
as sequence modeling very
generally.
Got it.
That sounds interesting.
So do you think we
can use some sort
of like Q-learning
objectives instead
of self-supervised learning?
It's possible.
And maybe like I'm
saying that for certain--
like for online RL it
might be necessary.
Offline RL, we were happy
to see it was not necessary.
But it remains to be
seen more generally
for transformer model or any
other model for that matter
encompassing RL more
broadly whether that
becomes a necessity.
Yeah.
Well, thanks for your time.
This was great.